A Fruit farmer is looking for ways to increase productivity
ある果物農家が、 製品 (果物) のすばらしい品質は確保したまま
while maintaining excellent product quality.
生産性を上げる方法を探しています。
To monitor and control growing conditions,
作物の生育状況を監視したり、コントロールするために
the farmer plans to install humidity and temperature sensors, and a sprinkler system.
その果物農家は、湿度センサーと温度センサー、 そしてスプリンクラーシステムを設置しようと計画しています。
Weather forecast data from an online web service
Webサービスからの天気予報データは、 Weather forecast data from an online web service
would also be useful in order to predict watering requirements.
給水の必要性を予測するために役立ちます。
The farmer decides to engage an IT consultant.
果物農家は、ITコンサルタントと相談することにします。
They would like to use the developer of their web presence to realize an IoT solution.
彼らは、IoTソリューションを実現するために、 Webデベロッパーを使いたいと思いました。
The developers at Web Agency like the new challenge
そのWebデベロッパーの開発者は、 この新しい挑戦が気に入りました。
They are experts in both web frontend and backend technologies using Node JS.
彼ら (デベロッパー達) は、Webフロントエンド技術と NodeJSを利用したバックエンド技術の両方のエキスパートです。
However, they are worried about the interoperability problems
しかし、彼らは、以前のIoTプロジェクトで経験した
that they experienced in a previous IoT project.
相互運用性の問題について心配しています。
After searching online for a solution,
ネットで解決方法について調べた結果、
the developers find information on the Web of Things, WoT
デベロッパー達は、Web of Things (WoT) に関する情報を発見します。
WoT is a W3C standard that enables Web developers to become IoT developers
WoTは、W3Cの標準で、Webデベロッパー達が使い慣れたツールやフレームワークを活用して
using the tools and frameworks they love.
WebデベロッパーがIoTデベロッパーになれるようにするものです。
WoT can be applied to many different IoT domains,
WoTは、様々な異なるIoT領域へ応用することが可能です。
such as Manufacturing or Building Automation,
例えば、製造業やビルオートメーションなどが挙げられますが、
but is also applicable to our farmer's problem in the Agriculture domain.
今問題になっている果物農家が抱えている、 農業の領域に関する問題に対しても応用可能です。
The developers are happy to find a bunch
Webデベロッパー達は、WoTに関する多くのチュートリアルが、
of WoT tutorials on thingweb.io, YouTube, and GitHub.
thingweb.io、YouTube、GitHubなどに置かれているのを見つけてうれしく思います。
With node-wot, various protocol bindings
その中には、node-wotのようなオープンソースの実装や、
like HTTP, MQTT, CoAP, and Modbus,
HTTP、MQTT、CoAP、Modbus等を含めた、 様々なプロトコルとのバインデングに関する情報
and a browser bundle, the developers easily create a full stack IoT solution.
そして、ブラウザーバンドルなどがあり、 Webデベロッパー達は、簡単にフルスタックのIoTソリューションを 作り出すことができます。
Their solution connects all the devices
彼らのソリューションは、 全てのデバイスを相互接続し、
and includes a great user interface built with web technology.
また、Web技術を利用した、 すばらしいユーザーインタフェースを含んでいます。
Instead of creating a one-off, proprietary solution,
デベロッパー達は、 IoTの構成要素を作るにあたって、
the developers use the WoT methodology to create IoT building blocks.
特注の作り込みによる独自ソリューションではなく、 WoTの手法を利用するというわけです。
These building blocks extend their existing Web technologies portfolio.
WoTの構成要素を利用することによって、 既存のWeb技術の資産が拡張されるのです。
Thing Descriptions, WoT application templates,
今や、WoTのThing Description、アプリケーションテンプレート、
and IoT semantics are now in the same portfolio of reusable modules
そして、IoTのセマンティックスが、 既存のWeb関連プロジェクトにおける
as HTML pages, JavaScript packages, or CSS from former web projects.
HTMLページ、JavaScriptパッケージやCSSと同様に、 再利用可能なモジュールの資産となったのです。
The main element of the WoT methodology
WoTの手法における主な要素は
is the Thing Description, also known as a Tee-Dee.
Thing Descriptionで、「TD (ティーディー)」とも呼ばれます。
TD like Identification, Data organization, Access, Units, Types, Interactions, Security or Relationships.
そして相互作用、セキュリティや関係性といった、 TDに含まれる情報によって解決できます。
Classical IoT projects usually cause high costs,
旧来のIoTプロジェクトでは、
especially due to the high integration effort
特に、デバイスやサービスにおける、 異なるデータモデルおよびプロトコルの統合化作業のために、
of the different data models and protocols of the devices or services.
通常、高いコストがかかってしまいます。
In contrast, with WoT the developers create the IoT solution in just a few sprints
それに対して、WoTを利用すれば、 TD、プロトコルバインディングやスクリプティングAPIを、
by combining WoT TDs, protocol bindings, and scripting with their web expertise.
彼ら自身の持つWebの専門知識と組み合わせることにより、 デベロッパーは、ちょっと頑張るだけでIoTソリューションを作り出せます。
This leads to reduction in development and maintenance costs,
これにより、開発とメンテナンスのコストを削減することができ、
saving time and money.
時間とお金の節約になります。
The developers gain confidence in IoT
デベロッパー達は、IoTに対して自信がつき、
and from now on consider themselves experts in both Web and IoT technologies.
これからは、自分自身のことを「WebとIoT技術の両方のエキスパート」 であると考えられるようになります。
Based on WoT the farmer's IoT project could be easy realized.
WoTを使えば、この果物農家のIoTプロジェクトは、 簡単に実現することができるでしょう。
Now the developers are ready to tackle their next IoT challenge.
デベロッパー達は、すぐに次のIoT関連の課題に 挑戦することができます。
And yes, WoT is THE methodology they will use!
そして，そうです! WoTこそが、彼らがこれから使う手法なのです!